# **Omoefe Joseph Ugboma**

Olodi, Apapa, Lagos Nigeria | https://github.com/Omoefe-Ugboma | +2348026426407 | jkomoefey23e@yahoo.co.uk

Personal portfolio website: https://omoefe-

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/omoefe-

ugboma.netlify.app/

joseph-ugboma-3236a625/

### **SUMMARY**

Dedicated software engineer with More than five years of experience in web and application development, and as well as a software specialist. And also, a JavaScript developer with strong hands-on in ReactJS and React-Native. Strong creative and analytical skills. Team player with an eye for detail. Strong collaborative skills and proven history of application development.

# **TECH STACK SKILLS**

FRONT-END SKILLS	BACK-END SKILLS	FRAMEWORKS	DATABASE / Methodologies
HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SASS Flexbox, Grid-Layout, Bootstrap, Source-Control (Git), REST APIs (GraphQL), CI/CD	PHP, Python, NodeJS, Java, Agile Scrum, MOB, Docker, Rest Service, Data Structure & Algorithms	Django, ExpressJS, ReactJS, VueJS, Redux, Laravel &	SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL, MS SQL Server),

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **PromateLink Solutions Limited** | Full-Stack Developer

2019 till date

- Designing, architecting and writing the front-end of our eCommerce application using ReactJS with a lot of reusable components.
- Collaborating with a 4-person engineering team in solving compatibility problems, and also eliminating technical issues and update development process records.
- > Built extensive test coverage for all new features, reducing the number of customer complaints by 10%.

Meta Data Technologies Limited | Full-Stack Web Application Developer [Remote]

May 2019 - Nov 2019

- Developed new React components for the customer facing web application, improving the average user time on page by 2 minutes.
- ➤ Built the next version of client web application to add new user designs and features using ReactJS, Spring-Boot, Spring-Security and reducing reported bug issues by over 15%.

# **Africa Prudential Plc** | Back-End Web Developer

Nov 2018 - May 2019

- > Writing back-end API endpoints for the front-end developer to consume.
- Also creating and structuring the database tables for the endpoint to use.
- Worked to support an existing software to guide users on how to use it and also document bug reporting on it.

Forte Soft Systems Limited [NIIT EDUCATION] | Senior Faculty Head

April 2015 – May 2018

- Provided robust, comprehensive lesson plans for two different classes simultaneously while providing regular, additional support to students when requested.
- > Taught over 100 students concurrently while providing a high degree of education customization when required.

EDUCATION			
Middlesex University   Information Technology and Business Information Systems	2014   London.		
National Institute of Information Technology   Honors Software Engineering (Java Technology)	<b>2011</b>   Lagos		
New Horizons   Diploma Software Engineering Practice	2015   Lagos		
THE AGILE ADVISOR NIGERIA   Certificate of Completion Agile Scrum Mastering	2019   Lagos		

# **PROJECTS**

# **Jacob Esuene Squash Club Web App**

- (Designed and coded the website (using HTML5, Bootstrap 4, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Laravel and MySQL) where players of popular squash games lovers comes to play weekly and monthly competitions).
- Responded to user feedback and issues to improve site functionality and build additional features including automatic menus fully customizable at the back-end (Admin Panel).

# **ESC BLOG WEB APP**

Full-Stack Responsive Blog - Designed and coded the blog website (using HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap 4, PHP, Laravel, and JavaScript, and more) where the site admin post new updates about the clubs and recent events.

Link: <a href="https://jesconline.com/blog">https://jesconline.com/blog</a> | July 2020 - August 2020